《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
我们要留下来
We're staying.
给他们好看
Give them hell.
比尔，不要这么做
Bill, don't do this.
我把一生都奉献给国家 奉献给雷诺兹总统
I've dedicated my life to this country, to President Reynolds,
-我是个完美的士兵 -处理掉所有的照片、档案
- I've been a perfect soldier, - Every photo, file. Get rid of all.
比尔，不要这么做
Bill, don't do this,
你留言给葛瑞先生
You left a message for Mr. Geary.
我会让你死得很难看
I'm gonna gut you, bow to stern,
我没有杀罗伊葛瑞！ 包威陷害我！
I did not kill Roy Geary! Bagwell set me up!
你以谋杀 罗伊葛瑞的罪名被逮捕
You are under arrest for the murder of Roy William Geary.
我的心理医生说 我必须面对你
My therapist said that I need to confront you...
让你知道被背叛的感受
...to let you know how betrayed I feel.
垂比云警局
This is the Tribune Police.
只要你做好工作 我们就忘记关于席尔斯的事
Just as long as you do your job, we'll forget about shales.
之后你就可以回科罗拉多 看你儿子卡麦隆
And then you can go back to Colorado and visit your son, Cameron.
不准你再提到他的名字
Don't you ever mention his name again.
你后面的朋友怎么办？
What about your friend there?
如果我们要死 也要死得轰轰烈烈
If we're gonna go down, might as well go down swinging.
-莎拉 -迈克？
- Sara. - Michael?
-你们差点就逃掉了 -喂？
- Almost made it. - Hello?
喂？迈克？
Hello, Michael?
-是你吗？ -站起来
- Is that you? - Get up.
转过去
Turn around.
转过去！
Turn around!
如果你打算杀我们，亚历 有种就看着我们的眼睛开枪
If you're gonna murder us, Alex, you'll have to look us in the eyes while you do it.
-闭嘴 -你已经逮到我了
- Shut up. - You want me, you got me.
让我弟弟走！
Let my brother go!
我不想要你们两个 我只想找回我的人生！
I don't want either of you. I just want my life back!
为此你要杀死 两个无辜的人？
You're gonna kill two innocent men to get it?
-那当然 -我们是美国边境巡警队
- Absolutely. - This is the United States Border Patrol,
放下武器，不准动
Drop the weapon and remain where you are,
放下武器
Drop the weapon,
美国边境巡警队 放下武器！
United states Border Patrol! Drop your weapon!
所有人各就各位
All agents hold your positions.
-我是调查局探员，他们已被我逮捕 -我不管你是谁
- I'm FBI. These men are in my custody. - I don't care who you are.
在确认身份前 放下你的武器，否则我们会开枪
Until we verify, you will drop your weapon or we will drop you.
你自己选择！
Your choice.
前进！
Move in!
双手抱头，快点！
Hands on your head now!
不准动！
Don't move.
这里有喝的吗？
You got anything to drink?
去后面找
Check the back.
不明驾驶K 这里是禁毒处
Unknown rider, unknown rider, This is DEA on guard,
无线电频率K
Radio frequency...
-“糟糕”是什么意思？ -我们被边境巡警队盯上了
- What do you mean "uh-oh"? - Border Patrol's on our ass, man.
-多久才到墨西哥？ -已经在墨西哥了，老哥
- How long till we get to Mexico? - We're already in Mexico, papi.
越过国界不是就不能K
I thought they couldn't follow...
-跟踪我们了吗？ -九一一事件后就可以
...once we cross the border. - Not since 9/11.
重复，不明驾驶K
I repeat: Unknown rider, unknown rider,
我们要怎么办？
What are we gonna do?
拉下绳子然后祈祷
Pull the cord and pray.
不要！
Oh, hell, no.
听着，如果把飞机降落 我们肯定会被逮捕
Look, we try and land the plane, we're pinched for sure.
如果跳伞呢？
And if we jump?
这里是沙漠上空
We're in the middle of the desert.
等我们着地后 巡警会很难找到我们
Patrol'll have a hard time trying to find us once we land.
如果我们着地的话
If we land.
你一定会着地的
Oh, you gonna land.
只是力道大小的问题
It's just a matter of how hard.
祝你好运，朋友
Good luck, amigo.
我们刚收到消息，逃犯K
We're receiving reports that escaped convicts,,,
（新闻快报）
,,, Lincoln Burrows and Michael Scofield, have been apprehended,,,
林克柏劳及迈克斯科菲尔德 在几分钟前
于美墨国界北方被逮捕
,,, just a few miles north of the U, S, -Mexican border,
调查局探员亚历曼宏 在美国边境巡警队的协助下
Federal Agent Alex Mahone, with assistance from the United States Border Patrol,,,
在不久前将两人羁押
,,, took the men into custody just a short time ago,
目前消息尚未完整
Now, not a lot of information available,,,
不过据说 逮捕两兄弟的过程顺利
,,, but the brothers were apprehended without incident,,,
当时他们正试图 从新墨西哥州沙漠逃往国外
,,, while attempting to leave the country through the deserts of New Mexico,
该地离伊利诺州 福克斯河州立监狱非常遥远
A long way from Illinois' Fox River State Penitentiary,,,
他们不到十天前 才自该监狱逃出
,,, where they escaped from less than 10 days ago,
这些一度被称为 福克斯河八人帮的犯人
The Fox River Eight, as the group of convicts were once known,,,
现在只剩下四人 只有班哲明富兰克林K
,,, are now down to four, as only Benjamin Miles Franklin,,,
费南多苏克、查尔斯帕托西克 和西奥多包威仍在逃
,,, Fernando Sucre, charles Patoshik, and Theodore Bagwell remain at large,
-警方指出剩下K -长官
- Officials say it's only... - sir?
他听说了，他想见你
He just heard, and he'd like to see you.
关回监狱
- Back behind prison walls,
全国通报专线 持续传来新消息K
Tips continue to pour in to manhunt's national hot line...
（借口）
（堪萨斯州普拉特 荣民酒吧）
- now down to four, as only Benjamin Miles Franklin,,,
现在只剩下四人 只有班哲明富兰克林K
费南多苏克 查尔斯帕托西克
,,, Fernando Sucre, charles Patoshik,,,
和西奥多包威仍在逃
,,, and Theodore Bagwell remain at large,
-愿你们平安 -警方指出剩下的K
- Godspeed, gentlemen. - Officials say it's a matter of days,,,
福克斯河逃犯 迟早会被关回监狱
,,, before the rest of the Fox River Eight are back behind prison walls,
全国通报专线 持续传来新消息
Tips continue to pour in to manhunt's national hot line,,,
警方认为其他四名逃犯 依然在美国境内
,,, and officials believe all four fugitives are still on American soil,,,
解除他们可能 已逃到墨西哥的疑虑K
,,, allaying fears that they may have escaped across the Mexican border,,,,
打扰一下，长官
Excuse me, sarge.
不知道你是否可以 帮弟兄的忙？
I was wondering if you could help a brother out.
帮什么？
With what?
我最近刚从 中东报效国家回来
I only recently returned from delivering democracy to the desert...
我在想你是否知道K
...and I was wondering if you could tell me...
要去哪里才能装义肢
...how a guy goes about getting one of those prosthetic jobbies.
你被送回国前 军方没帮你治疗吗？
Didn't they make you whole before they shipped you?
我只能说那个医生 治疗得很不完整
Well, let's just say the doctor made the bed, he just neglected to tuck in the sheets.
你最好去荣民医院排队等待
Best thing for you to do is go on down there to the VA, get in line.
就那么简单？
That simple?
对
Yeah.
不过等你收到帐单 就得想办法筹钱
Till they send you the bill, and you gotta pay it.
华府的那些浑蛋 送我们去替他们打仗
Those bastards in Washington send us to fight for them.
-他们却没人愿意帮我们 -真是不应该
- Not a damn one of them fights for us. - Man, that is a crime.
还好对我而言K
But luckily for me...
钱不成问题
...money is not the issue.
是吗？
Is that right?
我需要填哪些表格？
Any particular forms I might need in order to qualify?
你知道吗，同性恋先生？
You know what, Mr. Don't-Ask-Don't-Tell?
你既然有办法把你的头发K
You figured out how to dye that hair of yours...
染得这么娘
...up like a nancy all by yourself.
你肯定可以 自己想办法弄到义肢
You sure as hell can figure out how to get a prosthetic...
装在你的断手上
...for that stump of yours by yourself.
对，我想我知道 该从哪里下手
Yeah, I think I got a pretty good idea where to start.
（新墨西哥州拉斯克鲁塞斯 边境巡警拘留所）
（美国边境巡警）
（伊利诺州久利特 福克斯河州立监狱）
我身边是艾德波维卡 福克斯河监狱的新任典狱长
I'm here with Ed Pavelka, the new warden of Fox River Penitentiary...
林克柏劳 和迈克斯科菲尔德K
...where Lincoln Burrows and Michael scofield...
预计将在明日被送回此地
...are scheduled to be returned to some time tomorrow.
典狱长，柏劳在预计处死K
Now, warden, the escape happened a mere two days...
两天前越狱逃出
...before Burrows was scheduled to be put to death.
之前刑期已经延后一天 你认为会再度延后吗？
He's already been granted one day. Do you anticipate any further?
林克柏劳是 已定罪的杀人犯
Lincoln Burrows is a convicted murderer.
他越狱出去 已危害到全国民众
His escape has endangered the lives of civilians across this country.
他并非名流，也不是烈士
He is not a celebrity. He is not a martyr.
我可以保证之前 福克斯河上一任管理阶层K
And I can assure you that whatever leniency was afforded him and the other prisoners...
对犯人的宽大 将不再被容许
...under the old regime at Fox River will no longer be tolerated.
柏劳先生唯一可预期的是 监狱犯人要求的K
The only thing that Mr. Burrows can expect is what a jury of his peers demanded:
速斩速决
A speedy execution.
迈克斯科菲尔德呢？
And Michael scofield?
由于他越狱，加上教唆犯罪
With his escape, the aiding and abetting charges...
以及过程中犯下的重罪 加上他原本的刑期
...the felonies he's racked up along the way on top of his original sentence...
我想斯科菲尔德先生 将在狱中度过余生，谢谢各位
...I'd say Mr. Scofield will be spending the rest of his life behind bars. Thank you.
典狱长，再请教你一个问题
Warden, one more question, sir.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：死亡陷阱
（联邦调查局分局 伊利诺州芝加哥）
曼宏的电话在谁手上？
Who's got Mahone?
-恭喜长官 -有什么消息？
- Congratulations, sir. - What do you got?
伊利诺州矫正局打来
A call from the Illinois DoC.
他们要派人去接 柏劳和斯科菲尔德K
They're sending a contingent to collect Burrows and scofield...
带回福克斯河监狱
...take them back to Fox River.
提醒他们这是联邦案件 我们会负责运送K
Remind them this is a federal case, we'll handle transport. Now...
我有，但今年是选举年 树大招风，大家都想分杯眉
I did, but it's an election year. Collar this big, everybody wants a piece.
典狱长打电话请调查局长帮忙
Warden called in a favor to the Bureau chief.
他答应了 我们才会在这里
He okayed it, so here we are,
一小时内应该会抵达
Should be there in about an hour,
我要坐上运送囚犯的车辆
I wanna be placed in the prisoner-transport vehicle.
-为什么？ -照做就对了
- What for? - Just get it done.
长官，他们是重大嫌犯 而你逮到了他们
Sir, these were the big fish, and you brought them in.
你应该为此高兴
You should feel good about that.
是啊
Yeah.
对
至少我们在一起
Well, at least we're together,
这倒是真的
Yes, there is that.
你在想什么？
What are you thinking?
我在想爸爸
Thinking about the old man.
你知道，就是他想做的事
What he tried to do, you know.
被关起来 很难死得轰轰烈烈
Tough to go down swinging when you're locked in a box.
还没玩完 我们可以打一通电话
This isn't over yet. We're entitled to a phone call.
我们打给莎拉 如果爸说的资料在她手上
We make that call to sara and she has the information Dad said she has.
在一切定案之前 我们可以让你得到赦免
We can get you exonerated before this thing goes down.
-迈克K -喂！
- Michael, it's... - Hey.
我们有权利打一通电话
We're entitled to a phone call.
你们只有权乖乖坐着 直到正式被拘捕为止
You're entitled to precisely squat until you're officially in custody.
这要等你们回到福克斯河才会发生 所以乖乖坐好
And that won't happen until you're back in Fox River, so sit tight.
还没结束
It's not over yet.
还没有
Not yet.
这里到伊利诺州的路程不短
A lot of ground to cover between here and Illinois.
我是说K
I mean...
我们活着回到 福克斯河的机率有多大？
What are the chances we even make it to Fox River alive?
我在新闻上看到你，亚历
Saw you on the news, Alex,
-是吗？ -还有那对兄弟
- Did you? - The brothers too,
他们比我预期中K
They were a little more...
来得有生命
...breathing than I'd hoped.
边境巡警队来搅局
Yeah, well, Border Patrol showed up.
-我无能为力 -真的？
- Nothing I could do. - Really?
柏劳和斯科菲尔德 你现在看得见他们吗？
Burrows and scofield, can you see them from where you are?
-可以 -那就开枪杀了他们
- Yeah. - Then put a bullet in their heads,
-有人在看守他们 -我不管
- They're being watched. - I don't care,
有持枪警卫
By armed guards,
等他们回到福克斯河监狱 我们就完蛋了
They make it back to Fox River, it is over for all of us.
本国人最爱 坏人的精采故事
Not much more this country loves than a bad man with a good story,
你觉得媒体会等多久才会K
How much longer do you think it'll be before someone...
-开始访问他们？ -你到底有没有听清楚？
...puts a microphone in front of them? - Hey, are you listening?
这里的戒备森严 你的要求等于是叫我自杀
With the security here, what you're asking me to do is tantamount to suicide.
-你听得懂吗？ -我不是在请求
- Do you understand what I'm saying? - I wasn't asking anything.
那会表示你还有说话余地
That would imply you had a say in the matter.
完成任务 你就快可以回家了，亚历
Pull this off and you are halfway home, Alex.
你记得家的模样吧？
You remember what home is like, don't you?
西侧大道九十号 白色篱笆、红色大门
90 West End Avenue. White fence, red door.
离我的家人远一点！
You stay away from my family.
你的脸上有K
You got a little something on your...
来，我帮你
No. Here, let me.
我真是K
I'm so...
-抱歉我太直接K -没关系，谢谢
- Pardon my forwardness. L... - It's okay. Thank you.
平常我不会管闲事
Normally, I wouldn't intervene.
只是昨天我下班回家时
It's just, yesterday when I was... I got home from work...
我发现我的门牙塞着菜渣
...I found what looked like the Brazilian rain forest...
活像是巴西雨林
...Iodged between my two front teeth.
我当时心里只想着 这么多人，一定有人看到了
And all I could think about was the number of people who must've seen, and not...
却没有半个好心人告诉我
Not a damn one of them had the decency to tell me.
轻微牙缝过大
Mild diastema.
什么？
Excuse me?
第八、九颗牙齿间有小缝隙
It's a slight gap between your eight and nine.
就是你的门牙
Your two front teeth.
有时候会卡住食物 例如K
And that it sometimes can act as a magnet for food...
甘蓝菜、鲔鱼，还有米饭
...like broccoli and tuna, and sometimes rice.
或是开胃小菜
Or relish.
你真是才色双全
All this and brains too?
-你是牙医还是K？ -我？差多了
- What are you a dentist or a? - Me? No. Hardly, no.
不可能的
I could never.
-我的前夫他是K -一个浑蛋？
- My ex. My ex-husband, he was... - A bastard?
这也是
That too.
你去过意大利吗K
Have you ever been to Italy?
-我叫迪妮丝 -迪妮丝，真是好名字
- Denise. - Denise. That's a lovely name.
意大利人每天午餐都喝红酒
You know, in Italy they have wine every day with lunch.
可是美国人呢？ 我们和餐吞下的K
And what do we do in this country? We power our food down...
是咖啡因、二氧化碳 加高果糖玉米糖浆
...with caffeine, carbonation and high-fructose corn syrup.
再也没有人愿意 花时间享受美食
No one ever takes the time to enjoy things anymore.
迪妮丝，我是否有幸K
Denise, would you do me the honor...
能与你共进剩下的午餐？
...of enjoying the rest of your lunch with me?
我很乐意
I think I'd like that.
白酒或是红酒？
White or red?
（堪萨斯州格里利郡 地方法院）
由于财力有限 他没有逃亡之嫌
And with limited financial resources, he poses no flight risk...
除非他不想 因重大谋杀罪受审
Unless he'd rather not stand trial for capital murder.
被告已经证明 他很有能力K
The defendant has shown great resourcefulness...
用少量的钱长途旅行
...in being able to travel across country with little money.
没有理由相信 他不会故技重施
There's no reason he couldn't do it again.
如果不相信我 听听贝里克先生的话
If you don't want to believe me, believe Mr. Bellick.
你这个浑蛋盗贼
You thieving son of a bitch,
你最好跪下祈祷 我找不到你
You better get down on your knees and pray I never find you,
因为等我找到你，听好了 我会让你死得很难看
Because if I do, mark my words, I will gut you, bow to stern,
他发誓要杀死葛瑞先生 并说到做到
He promised to kill Mr. Geary, and then he kept that promise.
像被告这种人 不应该放任他在外面游走
A man like the defendant should not be out in society.
我同意，不得交保
I concur. Bail denied.
会是谁打来的？
Who would that be?
只有一个人
Only one person.
迈克，是我 昨晚这支电话响起
Michael, it's me. Listen, this phone rang last night...
我接起来 可是没有声音
...and I went to answer it, but I couldn't hear anything.
我不知道是不是你打来的
And I wonder if maybe it was you.
我不知道现在该怎么办 该不该留言
I don't know what I should do, if I should leave a message,,,
还是有谁在听
,,, or who might be listening,
我需要知道你是否平安 我要你知道我没有K
I need to know that you're okay. I need you to know that I'm not.
我没有在希拉丢下你 我出了事，而我K
I didn't leave you in Gila. Something happened to me and I don't...
我不知道现在该怎么办 我不知该去哪里
I don't know what to do. I'm not too sure where to go...
可是我知道你是我 唯一能信任的人，你一定要K
,,, but I know that you're the only person I can trust, and I need you to,,,,
你一定要平安无事，还有K
I need you to be okay, and...
我需要你，拜托
And I need you. Please.
待命接收边境巡警移送
Stand by to receive Border Patrol transport,
移送囚犯，待命
Incoming prisoners. Stand by.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
（新墨西哥矫正局）
亚历山大曼宏，调查局
Alexander Mahone, Bureau.
他们是我的犯人 我要亲自坐上K
These are my prisoners, and I will be personally escorting them...
-移送车护送 -你可以搭随行车
...in their transfer vehicle. - You can follow in a chase car.
我想你没有听清楚
I don't believe you heard me.
我要在车上陪同他们K
I'll be accompanying them in their tran...
能够上车的人只有 驾驶和两名警卫
The only people allowed in the van are the driver and two guards...
他们是受过 专业训练的护送警卫
...who've been trained and certified in prisoner transport.
你真的要逼我 去找你的上司吗？
Are you really gonna make me go over your head?
我甚至愿意帮你拨电话
I'll even dial the phone for you.
这是标准程序，曼宏探员
This is standard procedure, Agent Mahone.
我们必须尽可能控制住场面
We need to keep that environment as controllable as possible.
人越多，场面越难控制
The more bodies, the less control.
这些人也许知道 其他逃犯的下落
These men may have knowledge of the location of the other escapees.
我必须查出K
This is knowledge that I...
才能做好我的工作
I need to do my job.
而我的职务是要确保 这两名囚犯K
And my job is to ensure the safe and successful transfer...
安全地被移送成功
...of these two prisoners.
随行车就在外面
The chase vehicles are right outside.
这里是新墨西哥州 阿拉莫戈多的K
We're coming to you live from the Border Patrol facility,,,
边境巡警拘留所现场 林克柏劳K
,,, in Alamogordo, New Mexico, where Lincoln Burrows,,,
和迈克斯科菲尔德 将被移送回K
,,, and Michael Scofield are being transferred...
你最好有充份理由 为何那两兄弟还活着？
There better be a good reason why those brothers are alive.
工作不顺吗，比尔？
Bad day, Bill?
抱歉，我以为你是依然存在的人
Sorry, I thought this was someone who still existed.
-牛肉干的生意好吗，欧文？ -事实上现在行情看涨
- How's the jerky business, Owen? - It's looking good right about now.
你敢再打来，你就死定了
You call this number again, you're a dead man.
今天你如果没杀了两兄弟 你也死定了
You don't kill Burrows and scofield today, so are you.
你我心知肚明，不过算你幸运 我有办法救你
You know it and I know it, and luckily for you, I know how to save your ass,
（免持听筒）
两兄弟已经被移送了
The brothers are already being transferred.
你太迟了
You're too late.
事实上，移送车的所在地 还是如你所愿
Actually, the transport van is exactly where you want them to be, Bill.
-为何？ -为何？
- Why? - Why?
你要我帮忙 比尔，而我要恢复职务
You want my help, Bill? I want my job back.
我要可以直接呈报总统
That means direct access to the president,
-我只听命于她 -别得寸进尺，保罗，再见
- I report only to her, - You're reaching, Paul. Goodbye.
-不要拒绝我，比尔 -你以为这两兄弟
Don't shut me out, Bill, You think Burrows and Scofield,,,
会威胁到这个政权？ 我知道K
,,, are a threat to this administration? I know everything,,,
卡洛琳雷诺兹干过的所有勾当 所有的一切
,,, caroline Reynolds has ever done, Everything,
先别慌，我只要求K
Now, before you panic, all I am asking...
能把我原先的任务完成
...is to be allowed to finish the job that I started.
向总统和你证明
To prove to the president and to you,,,
我对这政权还是有贡献的
...that I am still an asset to this administration.
（计划？）
你有何计划？
What's your plan?
我在伊利诺州矫正局有个朋友 移送由他们承办
I have an old associate in the Illinois DOc, They're heading up the transfer,
一个内线是不够的
It's gonna take more than one guy on the inside,
如果他的职位够高就可以
Not if the guy's in the right place,
只要你一声令下 两兄弟上了厢型车
Bill, you give me the go-ahead on this and those brothers get in the van...
他们就只能等死
...it'll be the last thing they ever do.
（新墨西哥州矫正局）
我从来没做过这种事
I have never done that before.
那我们算是弥补过往的遗憾
Then I guess we was making up for some lost time.
山姆，我得问你 你结婚了吗？
I have to ask, sam, are you married or something?
我？没有
Me? No.
-你怎么会认为K -拜托
- What makes you think...? - Come on.
我长得也许平凡 但我不笨
I may be plain, but I'm not a fool.
通常和我在一起的男人 都是醉翁之意不在酒
Usually, the men I end up with are just looking for something, you know...
另有所求
...on the side.
迪妮丝，我唯一求的K
Denise, the only side I'm interested in...
只有你的心
...is the inside.
而你的心K
And that place within you...
可不平凡
...is not plain.
-我得回去上班了 -真的要吗？
- I have to get back to work. - Do you really?
我今晚要负责关门
I have to close tonight.
你下班后 我去接你如何？
How about I pick you up after?
我们可以一起吃晚餐
We can have dinner.
-你确定？ -迪妮丝
- Are you sure? - Denise.
我坚持
I insist.
-请说 -好消息
- Yeah? - Good news,
你得救了
You're off the hook,
保罗凯勒曼在阿布奎基外 已布下人马，准备攻击车队
Paul Kellerman has a team ready to move on the caravan just outside of Albuquerque.
好，那我们该怎么做？
Okay, so where does that leave us?
到时会有兵荒马乱的场面
When it goes down, there's sure to be a moment or two of chaos,
人员惊慌失措 四处枪林弹雨
A certain amount of confusion, lots of bullets flying...
我要你确保 保罗凯勒曼中弹身亡
I need you there to make sure Paul Kellerman catches one.
现在替自己湮灭证据 太早了吧？
A little early to be covering your tracks, isn't it?
当初的条件只提到那些逃犯
The escapees, that was our deal.
-就这样 -对
- That's all, - Right.
我们的协议
Our deal.
提醒我一下 我们的条件是说两兄弟K
Refresh my memory. Was our deal supposed to end with Burrows and scofield...
回到监狱 还是死于非命？
...going back to prison, or bleeding from a hole in their heads?
我们给你机会改正，亚历
We're giving you a chance to make this right, Alex.
让凯勒曼处理 让他当我们的欧斯华
Just let Kellerman take care of it. Let him be our oswald.
那我就是你的杰克路比
And that makes me your Jack Ruby.
杰克路比当初单枪匹马
Jack Ruby was working alone,
你还有美国政府 替你撑腰，亚历
You've got the support of the United States government behind you, Alex,
祝你在阿布奎基好运
Good luck in Albuquerque.
（让凯勒曼退役）
长官，我保证这件事 马上就会结束
I promise, sir, this'll all be over shortly.
之后就会恢复正常
And it'll be back to business as usual.
-你后悔吗？ -什么？
- Do you regret it? - What?
现在已经知道结果了 你会后悔帮我吗？
Knowing what you know now, do you regret helping me?
换成你，你也会来救我
You'd have done the same thing for me.
-你这么想？ -我这么知道
- You think? - I know.
你还没回答问题
You didn't answer the question.
我不后悔来救你
I don't regret the act.
只后悔后果竟是如此
Just how it turned out.
这是件预谋杀人案
We've got a premeditated murder on our hands.
你想把钱独吞 再杀了唯一证人
You wanted to steal money then kill the witness.
你到底是谁的律师？ 我说过不是我干的
Are you my attorney or theirs? I told you, I didn't do anything.
不，我只是解释 他们的理论
No, I'm just explaining their theory of what happened.
你向警方解释 你没有杀葛瑞
Your explanation to the cops that you didn't kill Geary...
是因为你忙着去偷 五百万国家的钱财？
...because you were too busy trying to steal 5 million in federally insured money?
可能对你不太有利
Probably not the best move.
-不过有好消息 -什么？
- But there is good news. - What's that?
检察官愿意谈条件
The DA is willing to offer a deal.
-二十五年刑期 -不要
- Twenty-five years. - No.
布拉德，他们会撤销重大杀人罪 不会有死刑
Brad, they'll drop the capital charge. No death penalty.
不要！
No!
-等我出狱都快六十五岁了 -你至少可以出狱
- I'll be almost 65 when I get out. - But you'd get out.
如果案子开庭 你极有可能K
If this case goes to trial, there's an excellent chance...
被判死刑
...you're sentenced to death.
我执业已久，布拉德 我可以告诉你
Now, I've been doing this a while, and I can tell you.
这种案子不可能有好结果
These things never go down good.
当法治体系要惩罚你时 无论如何都会达到目的
When the system wants you, they get you, one way or another.
条件一定要包括 让我在伊利诺州服刑
Part of the deal's gotta be I do my time in Illinois.
我才能见到我母亲
So I can be near my mom.
（新墨西哥州矫正局）
他们要带我们去哪里？
Where are they taking us?
另一个寄养家庭吧
Another foster home.
我不想走，我喜欢这里
I don't wanna go. I liked it there.
我知道
I know you did.
他们要我们搬家 是因为你吗？
It's because of you, the reason they're making us move?
因为你又惹上麻烦了？
- Because you were getting in trouble again? - Yeah, and I'm sorry.
（孩童与家庭服务局）
对，我很抱歉
我这一生似乎 一直在把你拖下水
Seems like I've been dragging you in trouble my whole life.
你也帮助过我
Pulled me out of some too.
对
Yeah.
-喂 -亚历，我是保罗凯勒曼
- Yeah? - Alex, Paul Kellerman.
-你和比尔金谈过了吗？ -对
- Have you spoken with Bill Kim? - Yeah,
他通知我了 你要在阿布奎基布局
Yeah, he filled me in. You're staging in Albuquerque.
听着，我现在跳进来帮忙
Listen, me jumping in at this point.
并不代表我赞同你的工作
It in no way reflects my feelings about the job you've been doing.
我只想告诉你这点
I just wanted you to know that,
当然
of course.
只要我们把任务完成
So long as we get the job done.
我们就能回到 家人身边，对吧？
We all get to go back to our families, right?
越快越好
The sooner the better.
我需要知道什么资讯？
So, what do I need to know?
昨晚我们首次披露 经过九天逃亡后K
As we first reported last night, after nine days on the run,,,
逃犯林克柏劳 和迈克斯科菲尔德
,,, fugitives Lincoln Burrows and Michael Scofield,,,
福克斯河八人帮 越狱的两名主脑
,,, two of the masterminds behind the desperate Fox River Eight escape,,,
在墨西哥边境附近 遭边境巡警逮捕
,,, were apprehended by Border Patrol officials near the Mexican border,,,
（被捕）
,,, and are being transferred back to Fox River Penitentiary today,
今天正被移送回 福克斯河州立监狱
官方指出柏劳 他原本即将K
Officials say Burrows, who was scheduled to die,,,
因谋杀雷诺兹总统的 胞弟戴伦斯史泰门处死K
,,, for the murder of Reynolds' brother, Terrence Steadman,,,
他的行刑日可能改期 最快在下周处死
,,, could have his execution date rescheduled for as early as late next week,
由于两人犯下的重罪
With the number of felonies the pair now face,,,
柏劳的胞弟 迈克斯科菲尔德K
,,, Burrows' brother, Michael Scofield...
（新墨西哥州，阿布奎基）
-前面怎么回事？ -我去瞧瞧
- What's going on? - Let me go check.
-怎么回事？ -稍后通知你
- What do you see? - I'll let you know.
移开这台货柜车要多久？
How much time is it gonna take to move this?
我已经派人处理了
I've got my men working on it now.
-前面怎么了？ -你在赶时间吗？
- What's going on up there? - Are you in a hurry?
我们需要帮助 把挡住的车移开
Hey, we need some help getting this rig out of the road.
林克
Linc.
快点
Come on.
好，假设我们打开了手铐 要往哪里逃？
All right, let's say we get the cuffs off. Where do we go?
-那里 -太轻松了
- There. - That's too easy.
来吧，迈克，把握机会
Come on. Come on, Michael, take it.
来吧，来吧
Come on. Come on.
把握机会
Take it.
把握机会逃走
Take it and run.
我们思考一下 警卫意外地留下钥匙
Let's think about this. The keys are accidentally left out.
门意外地开着
The door is accidentally left open.
-是我们唯一的机会 -是他们的机会
- It's our only shot. - It's their only shot.
他们没有借口杀人 除非我们逃走
They don't have an excuse unless we give it to them.
-情况如何？ -没动静
- How we doing? - Nothing so far,
-没动静？ -他们只在对谈
- None? - They're talking, that's all.
五分钟后他们没动作 你就移开卡车，说解决了
They haven't bitten in five minutes, you pull the semi, you tell them it's fixed.
-恢复交通 -之后呢？
- You release traffic. - And do what?
要兔子上勾 就要移动红萝卜，亚历
You want the rabbit to hop, move the carrot, Alex.
（邮局）
你来了
You showed.
绅士说到做到
A gentleman always does.
我们要去哪里吃饭？
Where are we going to eat?
你想去哪里 我们就去哪里
Wherever your heart desires.
不过有一件小事 我想请你帮忙
You know, there's just one teensy-tiny thing I've been meaning to ask.
尽管说
Anything.
转递地址是机密资料
You know, forwarding addresses are supposed to be confidential.
我真的不该这么做
I really shouldn't be doing this.
今天下午我们做的事 有很多是你不该做的
Well, you shouldn't have been doing a lot of things we did this afternoon...
可是我们两人 都还没有被抓到
...but neither of us has been "smited" down yet.
她住这里
There she is.
你的表妹听到她舅舅留给她的钱 一定会非常惊讶
I'd imagine your cousin'll be pretty surprised to hear about the money her uncle left her.
那是当然的
You can be certain of it.
山姆，我这么问 你别介意，但K
Sam, I hope you don't mind me asking, but...
你的手K
Your hand...
是怎么了？
...what happened to it?
抱歉，我不是想让你不舒服 我只是K
I'm sorry. I didn't wanna make you feel uncomfortable or nothing. I just...
我想了解你
I wanna know you.
我想了解你的一切K
I wanna know everything about you...
如果这是你的过去 我想知道你是怎么K
...and if this is a part of who you are, then I want to know how it...
天啊
oh, dear God.
我但愿你没看到它
I really wish you hadn't seen that.
（限邮局职员进入）
我都盘算好了 你和其他一些人
Here's what I'm thinking. You and some of the boys...
调到单独牢房来
...get yourself transferred to ad seg.
这样我们就能成天 玩拼字游戏、看体育节目
We can spend our days playing scrabble and watching Sportscenter.
-队长，我K -约一年半后
- Look, captain... - Then in a year and half...
你就推荐我加入工作计划
...you recommend me for those work-release programs.
之后剩下的刑期 我只要拉稻草、晒太阳
I can sweat off the rest of my time heaving hay and getting sun.
-所以K -不是自由，但差不多了
- That's why... - It ain't freedom, but it's close.
所以你才要求来这里坐牢？
Is that why you requested to be sent here?
要是我去其他地方 身为前狱警，我死定了
Oh, I go anywhere else as a former C.o., I'm a dead man.
但这里有人照顾我 给我最好的房间K
Here, I got men to watch my back, get me the finest accommodations...
-你不会有单独牢房 -我不在乎他们要我去哪儿
- They're not putting you in ad seg. - I don't care where they're putting me...
-有单独牢房就对了 -局势变了，队长
...take me to ad seg. - It's not like it used to be.
-狱警已经不是这里的老大 -什么意思？
- C.o.'s don't run the game anymore. - What do you mean?
典狱长换人了 他要改革，证明他K
This new warden. He's cracking down to prove he's serious...
不会偏袒任何人
...about showing preferential treatment.
他要拿你杀鸡儆猴
He's making an example out of you.
路易斯，这是哪里？
Lou, what the hell is this?
大牢房
Gen pop.
欢迎回家，老大
Welcome home, boss.
（墨西哥索诺兰沙漠）
（美墨国界南方四十里）
各位，准备上路了
Okay, everybody, we're moving out.
迈克，机会快没了 等卡车移走K
Window's closing, Michael, once the truck moves...
我们现在逃 等于允许他们杀死我们
If we run now, we give them permission to put a bullet in our heads.
我们留下，一周内我就被处死 你会被关一辈子
We stay, I'm dead within the week. You're locked up for life.
或是他们想出杀你的办法 相信我，他们绝对可以
Or until they find a way to get to you, and believe me they will.
如果回监狱 会多出几天的时间
If we go to prison, we'll have a few days.
就有机会联络莎拉
We'll have a chance to contact sara.
我们不知道莎拉的下落
We don't know where sara is.
莎拉也许已死了，迈克
Sara may be dead, Michael.
让我用我唯一的伎俩逃出去
Let me get us out of here the only way I know how.
-打斗？ -对
- Fighting? - Yeah.
拿钥匙
Get the keys.
-开始了K -收到
- Here we go. Here we go. - Copy that.
好，任务开始
All right, we're on.
注意，封锁交通
Heads up, Hold traffic,
封锁来车，好
Hold all traffic. Okay.
我们完全不知道 门后面是什么
We have no idea what's behind that door.
对
Nope.
-准备好了吗？ -没有，你呢？
- You ready? - No. You?
没有
No.
我们走
Let's go.
打开！踢开门！快点！
Get it open. Kick it open. Go.
所有人到隧道中！
All men to the tunnel!
祈祷这里还有另一个出口
Just pray there's another way out of here.
这边
This way.
他们进去了 往你的方向去了
Yeah, they're in, and they're heading straight for you.
-有武器吗？ -没有
- Armed? - No,
-你在哪儿？我去支援你 -你继续移动
- Where are you? I'll back you up. - Keep moving,
只要他们想逃离你 就会往我这边跑，他们被包围了
As long as they're running from you, they're running towards me. They are boxed in.
好
Yeah.
（堪萨斯州，奈斯市）
等一下
Oh, hold on one sec.
食物的钱我开支票好吗？ 因为我没有K
Could I write a check for the food, because I don't have...
你好，贺兰德太太
Hello, Mrs. Hollander.
人家说好女人难寻
They say a good woman is hard to find.
如果此话属实 你一定是K
Well, if that's true, you must be very, very...
好上加好的女人
...very good.
不要害怕
Don't be frightened.
泰迪回家了
Teddy's home.
往这边
This way.
他们临时改道 往路面上去了
They're improvising, heading toward the surface.
-往哪里走？ -不知道
- Where to? - I don't know.
听着，如果我们出事
Look, if something happens to us...
如果我们分开，一人逃不出去 答应我你会去找莎拉
...if we get separated, if one of us doesn't make it, promise you'll find sara.
-我们逃得出去的 -快答应我
- We're gonna make it. - Just promise me.
我答应，走吧
I promise. Come on.
（州立监狱 莎拉丹奎迪医师）
雷诺兹总统毁了你们的人生 也毁了我的人生
President Reynolds ruined your life. She ruined my life.
你们想搞垮这贱人 我就是最佳内线
If you wanna take the bitch down, you just found your inside man...
但现在是唯一的机会
...but it's gotta be right now.
我们走！动作快！
Let's go! Now!